PROFESSOR: All right.
Now, we built this whole A* things,
and you see there's a star in its
name, and star usually means optimal,
so I built this up to some giant
tortoise plus hare combination.
And the question is, is this thing we've
just build, is it even optimal?
Uniform-cost search was optimal,
greedy was not.
If we can't get optimality, why don't
we just stick with greedy?
It's simple.
Well, let's execute A* search and
see if anything can go wrong.
Well, our friend starts out with S,
backward costs 0, forward costs 0,
total costs 0.
So let's do backward costs
and total costs.
All right, so we pop that off.
We get S to A. And S to A has backward
cost 1, forward cost 6, total cost 7.
We have S to G, which looks like it has
backward cost 5, forward cost 0,
total cost 5.
All right, so what comes off?
S to G comes off.
We see it passes the goal
test and we return it.
Optimal cost 5.
Oops, right.
So the problem here is, we actually
got the wrong answer out of A*.
Why didn't we keep traveling down
the S to A path that was
going to turn out well.
It was going to be so cheap, 1 plus 3.
Why'd we stop?
We stopped because of this guy.
The heuristic says, abandon all hope, ye
who enter here, and we say, OK, you
can stay on the fringe now.
We're going to go do something else.
And so the problem is, this heuristic,
it's nice because it can push you
towards the goal, but it's dangerous
because if it tells you this is really
bad news, well, you won't explore
that area of the graph.
So what went wrong here is the actual
bad goal cost here was less than the
estimated good goal cost.
And in particular, this number 6
overestimated the expense, and silly
us, we listened to the heuristic.
So we need our estimates.
Our heuristic values, they need to
always be less than the actual cost.
So if it actually costs us 3 to get to
the goal, the heuristic, it can answer
0, it can answer 3, but it better not
say 6, or we're going to start being
so optimal.
PROFESSOR: So this is a key idea for
getting A star search to be correct.
It's the idea of admissibility.
And this has to do with whether you're,
it's kind of your heuristics
outlook on life.
If your outlook is bad, if you have a
heuristic which is pessimistic, we
call it inadmissible.
And an inadmissible heuristic is one
that always says you're farther than
the goal than you are, or maybe there's
some good path that says, oh,
that's terrible.
It's going to cost a million, right?
We saw that if the heuristic lies to you
and says that something costs more
than it actually does,
we can make mistakes.
So here's a case where pessimistic
inadmissible heuristics, they break
optimality.
An admissible, or optimistic heuristic
is one that always underestimates the
true costs, but hopefully
not by too much.
And these heuristics can
slow down a bad path.
They can say yeah, this
path is expensive.
I'm not sure how expensive.
Not more than this, but it is going
to be pretty expensive.
And when it tells you it's going to cost
at least eight, you believe it,
and you're safe in believing
it, right?
And so an admissible heuristic and slow
down the bad plans on the fringe.
It can keep them on the fringe for
longer, so you don't have to explore
what they lead to.
But in the end, the heuristic never
outweighs your true costs.
And that means the cheap stuff
will eventually win.
And so you'll eventually
do the right thing.
In math, a heuristic h is admissible,
or optimistic if
it's less than h star.
And h star is defined to be the true
optimal cost to a nearest goal.
So of course we build heuristic h.
They're little snippets of code that
execute them in compute h of n.
We don't know how to build
h star of n, right?
But it's a mathematical thing.
And so what you would do is you would
prove that the h that you have built
is less than h star, which
you can't build.
And then you know you're safe.
So here's some examples of
admissible heuristics.
We already saw one.
So on this kind of Pac-Man board,
the Manhattan distance.
Change in x plus change in y is
admissible because if there are no
walls, you could get there that fast.
But chances are the walls will
make you take some detours.
It's admissible in that it's
less than the true cost.
It may be a lot less than the
true cost, depending on how
tricky the maze is.
Here's pancake flipping.
I said I have to at least flip in order
to get, if the fourth pancake is
out of position, in order to get it in
position, I have to at least do a flip
of size four.
But I might have to do
a lot of other flips.
So here's a case where it's admissible
because it kind of keeps track of one
part of the solution.
But there may be a lot cell so the
solution that's going to cause you to
incur costs as well.
In practice, it's easy to define
what admissibility is.
Coming up with admissible heuristics,
which are lower bounds like this, but
are still accurate enough to be useful
in search is a big part of what's
involved in using A star in practice.
So people already know
the A star algorithm.
You're not going to publish a paper on
the A star algorithm very easily.
However, if you have a task that has an
interesting heuristic, that takes a
lot of work to figure out how A star
works in my case, because A star is
not a problem specific,
but your heuristic is.